# Ujwala Sangle

# Applying for: DevOps Engineer

& (+1) 8446729237 | ☑ ujwalasangle.official@gmail.com | 庙 LinkedIn

# **Professional Summary**

Ambitious Associate consultant with 3 years of experience with Capgemini in DevOpse and Big Data. Confident, motivated, dedicated DevOps Engineer possessing experience in technologies like AWS Cloud, containerization, CI/CD pipelines, and automation tools. Open to learn new technologies and ability to adapt new tool and environments quickly.

## **Experience**

#### **Associate Consultant**

Capgemini

05/2024 - Present

- Strong understanding of the Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) and Agile methodologies, ensuring efficient and iterative project delivery. Hands-on experience working with Kubernetes, including managing deployments, namespaces, and monitoring pods in a production cluster.
- Build Managed Elasticsearch clusters deployed on Kubernetes cluster for observability and log analytics.
- Developed and maintained GitLab CI/CD pipelines for automating build, test, and deployment processes across multiple environments.
- Implemented and configured Harness pipelines for continuous delivery and application deployment to Kubernetes clusters.
- Created and maintained Shell scripts to automate routine DevOps tasks such as automated job for daily snapshots, logging, and environment setup.
- Worked on setting up Kibana dashboards and alerts for system health monitoring using Elasticsearch data.
- Familiar with containerization concepts and Docker, used to build and push custom images for application deployment also Linux commands.
- Performed troubleshooting and debugging of Kubernetes pods, Elasticsearch nodes, and CI/CD pipeline failures.
- Set up Istio gateway/Ingress and service YAMLs to expose and access applications externally.

#### Analyst/Software engineer

Capgemini

07/2022 - 03/2024

- Have worked on AWS services like AWS Glue, Lambda, Step-function, S3 for processing
  data and stored the processed data in Snowflake which is further used by down-streams for reporting and used
  SNS and SES service for email notifications.
- Actively interacted and participated with client on the requirements/enhancements on daily basis.

#### **Education**

#### **Bachelor's Degree in Civil Engineering**

Pune

Vishwakarma Institute Of Information & Technology

2017 - 2020

Diploma in Civil Engineering

Chandwad

SHHJB Polytechnic College

2014 - 2017

### **Skills**

Aws Cloud services: AWS S3, Ec2, VPC, AWS EKS, AWS Lambda, AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM),

AWS Cloudwatch.

**CI/CD tools :** GitLab CI/CD , Jenkins, Harness pipelnes **Containerization & Orchestration:** Docker, Kubernetes

**Version Control:** Bitbucket, Git. **Security and Compliance:** IAM, VPC.

Log Management and Data Visualization: Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana

Networking & Traffic Management: Kubernetes Ingress

## Languages

Marathi (native), English (Fluent), Hindi(Fluent)